Olivia Stokes Hatch papers, 1859-1993 BMC.M86
Bryn Mawr College
Olivia Stokes Hatch papers
1859-1993
Bryn Mawr College
Hatch, Olivia Stokes, 1908-1983
BMC.M86
13 Linear Feet 13 containers, 1 photograph
The Olivia Stokes Hatch papers reveal the relief work of women during the early 20th century, as well as family relationships, largely illustrated through extensive family correspondence. Olivia Stokes Hatch (1908-1983) was born in New Haven, CT and attended Bryn Mawr College from 1925 to 1930. Prior to her marriage she was very active with the American Red Cross and American Conferences of Social Work. In 1939, Olivia Phelps Stokes married John Davis Hatch, Jr. an art collector, consultant, and museum director. They had four children: John Davis Hatch III, Daniel Lindley Hatch, James Stokes Hatch, and Sarah Stokes Hatch. Anna V.S. Mitchell, the sister of Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, and the aunt of Olivia Stokes Hatch, spent most of her life engaged in relief work. Her career began in 1915 in Serbia and ended in 1936 in Constantinople. The Olivia Stokes Hatch papers, 1859 to 1993, is a collection that consists largely of correspondence between the Phelps, Stokes, Mitchell, and Hatch families. The collection also includes photographs, essays, diaries, and other printed material. The collection is divided into three series: "Olivia Stokes Hatch," "Anna V.S. Mitchell," and "Collected Correspondence."
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research use.
Biographical note
Olivia Stokes Hatch (née Olivia Egleston Phelps Stokes) was born in New Haven, Connecticut, in 1908, and attended Bryn Mawr College from 1925 to 1930. Active in the Christian Association, she served a term as president of the Self-Government Association. Her family, an illustrious group, included: her father, Anson Phelps Stokes, a respected theologian and author of Church and State in the United States; her brother, Anson Phelps Stokes, Jr., the Episcopal Bishop of Massachusetts.; her brother, Isaac Newton Phelps Stokes II, a philanthropist, and her mother, Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, whose sister was Anna V.S. Mitchell, a relief worker during World War I. In 1939, Olivia Phelps Stokes married John Davis Hatch, Jr. an art collector, consultant and museum director who worked at the Art Institute of Seattle from 1928 to 1931, the Isabella Stewart Museum in Boston from 1932 to 1935, the Albany Institute of Art and History from 1940 to 1948, and the Norfolk Museum of Art and Sciences in Virginia, also known as the Walter Chrysler Museum, from 1950 to 1959. They had four children: John Davis Hatch III, Daniel Lindley Hatch, James Stokes Hatch, and Sarah Stokes Hatch.
Before her marriage, Mrs. Hatch was very active with the American Red Cross and American Conferences of Social Work. During the 1940s, she worked with the League of Women Voters, City Club (Albany), Race Relations group, and the Red Cross Speakers Bureau. In the 1950s, she worked with the Norfolk League of Women Voters, and was active in church groups and the Parent-Teacher Association. In Lenox, Massachusetts, in the 1960s, she volunteered as a reader for Recording for the Blind, and helped to entertain young artists in conjunction with the Berkshire Music Center. She also traveled throughout the United States, Central and South America, and in the Far East. She is a co-author, with Mary Marvin Breckinridge Patterson, of Olivia's African Diary: Cape Town to Cairo, 1932, which describes their trip throughout Africa and was published in 1980.
She died on October 10, 1983. John Davis Hatch, Jr. died in 1996.
Anna V.S. Mitchell, sister of Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, spent most of her life engaged in relief work. She was heavily involved with domestic fundraising efforts on behalf of Russian refugees in Constantinople and relief aid throughout World War I. Her career began in 1915 in Serbia and ended in 1936 in Constantinople.
Custodial History note
Gift of John Davis Hatch, 1984.
Related Materials
Archives of American Art: John Davis Hatch papers, 1790-1995.
Hoover Institutional Archives: Register of the Anna V.S. Mitchell papers, 1920-1944.
National Museum of African Art: M. Marvin Breckenridge Patterson photographs, 1932.
Schlesinger Library, Radcliffe Institution: Caroline Phelps Stokes papers of Caroline and Olivia Phelps Stokes, 1854-1927 [MC 187]; Caroline Phelps Stokes papers, 1892-1927 [MC 188].
Yale University: Anson Phelps Stokes family papers, 1761-1960, bulk 1892-1958 [MSS 299].
Scope and Contents note
The Olivia Stokes Hatch papers is a collection that consists largely of correspondence between the Phelps, Stokes, Mitchell, and Hatch families. The collection, which ranges from 1859 to 1993, also includes photographs, essays, diaries, and other printed material. It provides insight into women's work during World War I.
The collection is divided into three series: "Series I: Olivia Stokes Hatch," "Series II: Anna V.S. Mitchell," and "Series III: Collected Correspondence." Each of these series is divided into subseries.
"Series I: Olivia Stokes Hatch," is divided into five sub-series: "Biographical Information;" "Collected Personal Material;" "Correspondence;" "Family Material;" and "Photographs." "Biographical Material" includes clippings about Olivia Stokes Hatch and written accounts of her life and work. Within "Collected Personal Material," are items such as address books, notebooks, and elementary and high school yearbooks. The third sub-series is "Correspondence." As noted, the largest component of this collection is Olivia Stokes Hatch's family correspondence and it is arranged into outgoing and incoming sub-series, according to the principals in the Phelps, Stokes, Mitchell, and Hatch families. The sub-series includes the extensive correspondence of Olivia Stokes Hatch, her father and mother Anson Phelps Stokes and Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, her husband John Davis Hatch Jr., and their children John Davis Hatch III, Daniel Lindley Hatch, James Stokes Hatch, and Sarah Stokes Hatch. Also included within the correspondence is the correspondence of Gethel Gregg Hatch, John Davis Hatch Sr., and other friends and relatives. Topics discussed in the correspondence include family relationships, work in the Red Cross, and travel. Researchers may also wish to review the correspondence within the "Anna V.S. Mitchell" series, as well as the final series, "Collected Correspondence," when studying the family correspondence. The fourth sub-series within "Series I: Olivia Stokes Hatch," is "Family Material." This sub-series includes childhood keepsakes of Olivia Stokes Hatch and John Hatch Jr.'s children, press releases and reports regarding the Phelps-Stokes Fund. Also found within "Family Materials" are the wills and estates of Anson Phelps Stokes and Olivia Stokes Hatch. The fifth subseries within "Series I: Olivia Stokes Hatch" is "Photographs," which consists of images of Olivia Stokes Hatch and her family, as well as locations in Egypt and across the United States.
"Series II: Anna V.S. Mitchell," refers to the sister of Olivia Stokes Hatch's mother, Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes. This series is divided into five sub-series: "Biographical Information;" "Correspondence;" "Collected Material;" "Diaries;" and "Essays." "Biographical Material" contains travel documents and accounts of Anna V.S. Mitchell's work during and after World War I. The second sub-series within "Series II: Anna V.S. Mitchell" is "Correspondence." Again, correspondence is a large component of this series, documenting the relationships of the Mitchell family. The sub-series includes the correspondence of Anna V.S. Mitchell, her sister Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, Anson Phelps Stokes and Olivia Stokes Hatch, and other relatives and friends. Much of the correspondence is regarding her work during World War I and domestic fundraising efforts on behalf of Russian refugees in Constantinople. When reviewing this correspondence, researchers may also be interested in examining the final series in the collection, "Collected Correspondence," for additional information. Following "Correspondence" is Anna V.S. Mitchell's "Collected Material," which contains publications, notes, and records of her life and specifically, World War I. Of note in this sub-series are excerpts of her letters from July 1916 to May 1919, that have been transcribed. The fourth sub-series within "Anna V.S. Mitchell" is "Diaries." Her diaries provide an intimate and firsthand account of her work and experiences in World War I. The diaries date from 1896 through 1925. The final sub-series is "Essays" and here researchers will find her handwritten reflections and recollections of her relief work.
The final series in this collection is "Series III: Family Correspondence." This series contains the correspondence of Sarah Lindley Mitchell, Lucy Mitchell Molteno, Sarah Rood, and other members of the Mitchell and Stokes families.
This collection is an excellent resource for those researching family dynamics and relationships in the early to mid 20th century. The collection also provides an intimate look into the relief work of women during World War I through correspondence and diaries created by those involved directly. The work of women in the American Red Cross is also well documented through correspondence within the collection.
War work; World War, 1914-1918; publications (documents); Refugees; Diaries; Photographs; Egypt; Correspondence; Istanbul (Turkey); Wills; yearbooks; family papers; Travel; Bryn Mawr (Pa.); Serbia; Estate records; Travel photography; Hatch, David Lindley; Ruggles, Alma; Thierry, Mary Mills; Stokes, Caroline Green Mitchell; Stokes, I.N. Phelps (Isaac Newton Phelps); Hatch, Gethel Gregg; Mitchell, Clarence Green; Mitchell, Anna V.S.; Hatch, John Davis, Jr., d. 1996; American Red Cross; Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1874-1958; Stokes, Helen Louisa Phelps, 1846-1930; Mitchell, Clarence Blair, b. 1865; Stokes, Olivia Egleston Phelps, 1847-1927
- Series I. Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1859-1983
  - Subseries a. Biographical Information, 1908-1983 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Subseries b. Collected Personal Material, 1906-1983
    - Address Books, undated (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    - Educational Material-General, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Educational Material-Advanced Standing Examination in French Reading and Composition, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Educational Material-Poem "The Yearning to Create" written in English class at Bryn Mawr College, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Educational Material-Tally-Ho! (Yearbook), 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Educational Material-Tally-Ho! (Yearbook), 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Invitations to Events sent to Olivia Stokes Hatch, undated (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
    - Lock of hair (unidentified), undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Notebooks, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Notebooks, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Programs, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Social Diaries, 1920, 1934, 1935, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Telephone Book, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Travel Materials, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Subseries c. Correspondence, 1906-1983
    Correspondence
    The letters in the "Correspondence" series are arranged into outgoing and incoming sub-series, according to the principals in the Phelps Stokes, Mitchell, and Hatch families.
    - Anson Phelps Stokes to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1906-1922 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - Anson Phelps Stokes to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1923-1927 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Anson Phelps Stokes to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1928-1951 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Anson Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1921-1933 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Anson Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1937-1956 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Anson Phelps Stokes, 1918, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1921-1925 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1931-1933 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1936-1938 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1941-1943 April (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1943-1945 May (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1943 May-1945 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1946-1948 May (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1948 July-1949 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1950-1951 October (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1951 November-1952 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1955-1957 April (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1957 September-1960 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch-Fragments, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes to Lou Lou, Sade, John Davis Hatch Jr., and others, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Clarence Blair Mitchell to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1933-1938 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Clarence Blair Mitchell to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1939-1941 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Clarence Blair Mitchell to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1944-1948 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Clarence Blair Mitchell to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1949 January-1949 June (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Clarence Blair Mitchell to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1949 July-1950 March (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Clarence Blair Mitchell to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1950 April-1950 December (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Clarence Blair Mitchell to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1951-1954 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Clarence Blair Mitchell to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes-Fragments, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Clarence Blair Mitchell correspondence with others, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Anson Phelps Stokes Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch and others, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Anson Phelps Stokes Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch and others, 1943-1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Anson Phelps Stokes Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch and others, 1926-1960 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Isaac Newton Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch and others, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Isaac Newton Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch and others, 1940-1968 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Isaac Newton Phelps Stokes to Olivia Stokes Hatch and others, 1960-1978 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Anson Phelps Stokes, 1926-1958 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1916-1925 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1926-1930 (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1931-1935 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1938-1939 May (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1939 July-1941 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1942-1945 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1940-1945 (Box 3, Folder 21-22)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1945-1948 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1945-1949 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1952-1954 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1955-1956 September (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1956 October-1957 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, undated (Box 3, Folder 32-34)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Anson Phelps Stokes and Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1926-1949 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Anson Phelps Stokes and Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1950-1960 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Anson Phelps Stokes Jr. and Hope Proctor Stokes, 1938-1958 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Isaac Newtown Phelps Stokes and his wife, 1932-1976 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Gethel Gregg Hatch and Family, 1943-1949 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Gethel Gregg Hatch and Family, 1950-1951 June (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Gethel Gregg Hatch and Family, 1951 July-1951 December (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Gethel Gregg Hatch and Family, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Gethel Gregg Hatch and Family, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Gethel Gregg Hatch and Family, 1954-1956 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Gethel Gregg Hatch and Family, 1957-1965 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Doris (Hatch) Munster, 1943-1951 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Relatives, 1920s to 1983 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch to Friends, 1926-1979 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch official correspondence and fragments, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Olivia Stokes Hatch fragments, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - John Davis Hatch Sr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch and John Davis Hatch Jr., 1940-1955 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Gethel Gregg Hatch to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1940-1944 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Gethel Gregg Hatch to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1945-1946 October (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Gethel Gregg Hatch to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1946 November-1947 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Gethel Gregg Hatch to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Gethel Gregg Hatch to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1950-1953 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Gethel Gregg Hatch to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1954-1964 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Gethel Gregg Hatch to Hatch family, 1939-1944 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Gethel Gregg Hatch to Hatch family, 1945-1949 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Gethel Gregg Hatch to Hatch family, 1950-1953 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Gethel Gregg Hatch to Hatch family, 1954-1963 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Gethel Gregg Hatch to John Davis Hatch Jr., 1939-1949 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Gethel Gregg Hatch to John Davis Hatch Jr., 1950-1959 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - John Davis Hatch to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes and Anson Phelps Stokes, 1939-1959 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1939 February-1939 April (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1939 May-1939 July (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1939 August-1940 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1941-1943 June (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1943 July-1943 October (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1948-1950 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1955 January-1955 August (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1955 October-1956 August (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1956 November-1957 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1960-1964 October (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1964 November-1965 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1966-1968 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1969-1983 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. to Gethel Gregg Hatch, John Davis Hatch III, David Lindley Hatch, and James Stokes Hatch, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - John Davis Hatch Jr. Professional Writing Correspondence, 1939-1978 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Mary Mills Thierry to Olivia Stokes Hatch and John Davis Hatch Jr., 1939-1965 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Doris Hatch Munster to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1939-1960 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Doris Hatch Munster to Olivia Stokes Hatch and John Davis Hatch Jr., 1939-1957 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - John Davis Hatch III to Olivia Stokes Hatch and John Davis Hatch Jr., 1954-1977 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Daniel Lindley Hatch, James Stokes Hatch, and Sarah Stokes Hatch to Olivia Stokes Hatch and John Davis Hatch Jr., 1951-1983 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Lael Munster and Joseph McCormack to Olivia Stokes Hatch and John Davis Hatch Jr., 1949-1952 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Associates (including Richard P. Strong) to Anson Phelps Stokes, 1915-1916 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Sarah Lindley to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1916-1948 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Lucy Armitage to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1938-1956 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Relatives to Carolina Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1913-1958 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Relatives to Carolina Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1918-1960 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Friends to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1916-1932 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Friends to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1933-1950 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Friends to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Friends to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1952-1962 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Friends to Caroline Mitchell Phelps Stokes, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Relatives to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1925-1945 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Relatives to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1951-1974 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - "Nanny" to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1928-1945 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Relatives to Olivia Stokes Hatch and John Davis Hatch Jr., 1951-1982 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Friends to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1922-1925 August (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Friends to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1925 September-1926 October (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Friends to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1926 November-1927 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Friends to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1928-1930 March (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Friends to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1929-1930 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Friends to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1930 April-1930 December (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Friends to Olivia Stokes Hatch, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 7)